ISAIAH **FRANCOIS** FULL STACK

francoiscoding.netlify.app/

**** 3529893703

ENGINEER

♀ Clermont, Fl

in francoiscoding

FrancoisCoding

A software development and performance engineering expert with 2+ years of experience in developing quality assured applications and supervising/training students. A collaborative developer and engineer with experience and education in the hardware and software sides of technology who thrives on discovery and accelerating performance.

Skills

PROGRAMMING TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

Python

ReactJS

Express

SOL Redux

SASS

MongoDB

Firebase

Cypress Testing

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Teamwork and Cross-functional Communication

Adaptability

Technical Troubleshooting and Debugging

Software and Engineering Documentation

Systems Architecture and Operations

Teamwork and Crossfunctional Communication

Performance Engineering

Projects

DevChat

Solo full-stack chat application allowing users to chat in real-time and video call any user across the platform.

Firebase| React.JS | Semantic UI | Redux | Moment

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can have conversations and video call.
- Utilized the Jutsu Video API in order to establish video connections between users

Al Application

Solo full stack AI application that can conversate, provide latest news updates, and provide amazing calculations.

React.JS | Alan-Al

• Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can have conversations with Alan the Al and request for latest news updates

• Utilized the Alan API in order to create scripts for AI to recognize and respond to user

Coach Me Health

Patient first non-profit organization dedicated to improving the health of low-income Americans with diabetes and heart disease with health coaching for those who need it most.

ReactJS | Redux | SASS | Twillio | Cron Jobs | ChartJS | Cypress

• Collaborated remotely with a team of 7 Web Developers and 2 UX/UI Designers to build a

fully functional web application over the course of 8 weeks.

• Utilized Twilio's API alongside Cron Jobs to schedule messages to be sent to clients on the backend (Node.js) in order to communicate with users efficiently.

React Movies

Solo IMDB style Web Application that provides up to date movie information and details.

ReactJS | Bootstrap

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view information on over 10,000 of the latest movies released.
- Utilized The Movie Database API in order to display all information about latest movie titles to users

Francois Games

Solo gaming platform featuring over 400,000 game titles with information to purchase game, gaming clips, thumbnails, developer information, and more.

ReactJS | Bootstrap | Material UI | Styled-Components

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a platform where users can view over 400,000 game titles.
- Utilized the RAWG Video Games Database API in order to display all information about latest video game titles to users.

Beach Resort

E-commerce application featuring a hotel where users can view featured rooms, filter through rooms, receive updated room information and book rooms through PayPal

React.JS | Contentful | Redux | PavPal

- Solely responsible for creating the entirety of the application which includes a e-commerce platform where users can book a room at a virtual hotel.
- Utilized the Contentful CMS to create database to store rooms and the PayPal API to initialize user purchasing

Employment

Lambda School

Remote Oct. 2019 to July 2020 Team Lead

- Mentored 10+ students on how to learn effectively and solve programming problems.
- Provided daily feedback and issue resolution of all curriculum through Slack interface. • Led daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, facilitate sharing of ideas and work
- progress, and provide guidance for that week's study material.
- Delivered one-on-one feedback and code review on a weekly basis, giving feedback on
- areas of improvement.

SpeechifAl

Lead Front-end Developer

Remote Feb. 2021 to Current, Feb. 2021 to Current

- Build world class experiences for our for clients
- Build, iterate, and maintain interactive web pages, editable landing pages, and unique user experiences
- Own the front end development across multiple sites
- Leverage in-house APIs (REST) to build dynamic, interactive pages
- Work with Marketing UI/UX designers to translate designs into pixel perfect code
- Be the expert on viability and approach to web projects
- Define and estimate work effort and duration
- Grow technical knowledge by researching the latest development methods and techniques, sharing that information with your team and creating development plans for them to grow within in their current realm and in use of new technology

Education

Lambda School · May 2019 to Feb. 2020 Full Stack Web Development

Remote